bradford.ac.uk 2018-05-15

# Privacy and Cookie Policy - University of Bradford

## Revision date: 9 February 2015

This privacy policy sets out how University of Bradford uses and protects any information that you give the University of Bradford when you use this website.

University of Bradford is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement and the Data Protection Act.

University of Bradford may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 25 May 2012 to comply with the EU Cookie Law which comes into effect on 26 May 2012. See the [Information Commissioners Office website](https://ico.org.uk/media/for-organisations/documents/1545/cookies_guidance.pdf "Information Commisioner's website.") for full details (pdf).

## What we collect

We may collect the following information:

  * name
  * job title
  * contact information including email address
  * demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
  * other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers
  * information publicly held about companies e.g. number of employees, turnover, VAT number

## What we do with the information we gather

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Internal record keeping
  * We may use the information to improve our products and services
  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests

Further information is available from our Data Protection pages.

## Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

## How We Use Cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We sometimes use a cookie to remember colour preferences on the website, which can be set so that it is easier to read for people with visual impairments.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about webpage traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs.

We also use some cookies provided by third parties, namely YouTube and AddThis (the social media sharing tool that we use on some of our web pages). Further information about the cookies we use is below as is information about how to change your own browser settings to opt out of cookies being placed on your computer.

### Cookies are safe and secure

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages users as a whole find useful and which they do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. Cookies are completely safe and secure and will never contain any sensitive information.

### Accept or Decline Cookies

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. However, this may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

For further information about deleting and controlling cookies see [AboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/ "About Cookies dot org link.")

### The cookies we use

Provider| Name| Description and further information  
---|---|---  
Google Analytics | 

__utma

>__utmb

__utmc

__utmz

| 

 Google Analytics uses cookies to define user sessions, as well as to provide a number of key features in the Google Analytics reports.

See the [Cookies and Google Analytics](https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsCookies "Cookies and Google Analytics.") web page for full details.  
  
 AddThis |  _atuvc | 

 To enable numbers of shares to be registered.

See the [AddThis Privacy Policy](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/privacy-policy#.T79y6bA9Asc "AddThis privacy policy.") for full details.  
  
## Links to other websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy and cookie statement. You should exercise caution and look at the statements and policies applicable to the website in question.

## Controlling your personal information

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

Whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, or other hard copy form, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes.  If you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at [removeme@bradford.ac.uk](mailto:removeme@bradford.ac.uk "Email removeme@bradford.ac.uk")[  
](mailto:web-team@bradford.ac.uk "Email the Web Team.")

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.

Data Protection Officer  
University of Bradford  
Bradford  
BD7 1DP

## Third-party access

Your personal data may be forwarded to third parties in connection with the purposes outlined elsewhere in this statement, to be used on behalf of the University of Bradford. These organisations will only use your personal on behalf of the University of Bradford, in accordance with their own Data Protection or Privacy policies and the terms of agreement with the University of Bradford. Organisations currently carrying out work on behalf of the University include 11Ten and Hobsons.

  * 11Ten Data Protection Policy (Word doc, 40KB)
  * Hobsons Information Security Program (PDF, 217KB)

## Bulk emails

From time to time we email our alumni, prospective students, business partners, schools and colleges and others who have signalled their willingness to hear from us, with details of new courses or forthcoming events, news about the University, and related information. Some bulk emails are sent via technologies that allow us to track which subscribers have read them. To be removed from a list of subscribers, or to stop receiving any communications from us, please email [removeme@bradford.ac.uk](mailto:removeme@bradford.ac.uk "Email address to be removed from mailing lists.") or use the link an an email that has been sent to you

* * *

## Marketing Communications Privacy Policy

The University of Bradford wishes to communicate with those people who have expressed an interest in studying at the University (enquirers) and current applicants in order to keep them informed of areas of information that may be of interest and help them to make a decision about whether to study at the University.

Areas of information we wish to inform you about include, but are not limited to, university rankings; testimonials from current students and alumni; accommodation; fees, finance and scholarships; on-campus events; key dates in the application process; information about the city of Bradford and the surrounding location as well as any other information the University feels may be of relevance to you.

The University will communicate via a variety of channels which will be determined by the contact details provided by you – these include, but are not limited to, email, telephone, SMS, Whatsapp, Skype, Social Media channels and Direct Mail.

From time to time the University may contact you requesting your participation in market research surveys in order to enhance and improve our application process, communication channels and academic programmes.

The University may analyse your personal information to create a profile of your interests and preferences so that we can ensure that the information we contact you with is relevant to you.

If you have provided your information in order to attend an event at the University we will use that information to provide you with details about that event. If you do not wish to receive any further information from us you will be able to opt out of those communications at the time of registering for the event.

**Under what legal basis does the processing of my personal data take place?**

The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) as enshrined into UK law by the Data Protection Act 2018 provides for a number of different legal bases under which processing of personal data may take place.  In this case, the following bases apply:

  * **_Consent (enquirers):_** when you provide us with your details we will ask for your consent to use those details to carry out the activities as detailed above. If you no longer wish to receive these communications you can withdraw your consent at any time by contacting the University at MarketingComms@bradford.ac.uk or updating your preferences in the Your Bradford portal.
  * **_Necessary in order to take steps at your request prior to entering into a contract (applicants)_** : as you have applied for an academic programme, the University will provide you with information to help you decide whether to accept an offer of a place, should the University choose to make you one.
  * **_Necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests (applicants):_** we process personal information for certain of our own legitimate business purposes. We will not process your data for the legitimate interests of any third parties. These interests include some or all of the following:  
\- where the processing enables us to enhance, modify, personalise or otherwise improve our services / communications for your benefit  
 \- to better understand how people interact with our websites   
\- to provide communications which we think will be of interest to you (direct marketing)  
\- to determine the effectiveness of promotional campaigns and advertising.   
These legitimate interests do not override your own interests as they are to provide you with the services and information you may need to make the right decision on where you choose to study. However if you would like us to stop using your information in this way please contact the University at [MarketingComms@bradford.ac.uk](mailto:MarketingComms@bradford.ac.uk) or update your contact preferences in the Your Bradford portal.  
Please bear in mind that if you make a request to us to stop using your information this may affect our ability to carry out tasks above for your benefit.

**What categories of personal data are used?**

All information necessary to provide you with relevant information with regards to your interest in the University of Bradford, this might normally include but is not limited to:

  * Name
  * Contact Details
  * Date of Birth
  * Postcode
  * Study Level (e.g. UG, PG, Foundation, Research, CPD or other)
  * Subject area of interest
  * Country of domicile, Nationality and/or UK residency status
  * Anticipated year of entry for study
  * Current educational status or qualifications.
  * Disability status
  * Original enquiry source (e.g. UCAS fair, school event or through our website)
  * Academic programme applied for
  * Current school or college (where relevant)
  * Application status (e.g. offer made, offer accepted or offer declined)
  * Details of any specific questions you ask of us

**Where do we get your personal data from?**

  * Personal data will be provided by you either:  
\- Directly in the course of making an enquiry for or at an event, through the University website or by making an application to study at the University.  
\- Indirectly in the course of making an enquiry through an agent, external information providers such as WhatUni or Hotcourses or any other providers where you submit your details to be provided with information from the University.  
\- Indirectly in the course of making an application through UCAS or an agent.

**Who else do we pass this information on to?**

Your personal data will only be shared with those third parties with whom the University works in order to provide you with relevant, personalised communications. These types of organisations can include but are not limited to:

  * Suppliers of digital content for emails
  * Service providers who send out emails, SMS, direct mail or other communications on behalf of the University
  * Providers who will use your profile information to identify others who may be interested in the University.

No information will be passed to third party organisations for them to contact you directly themselves.

**Do we transfer the information overseas?**

Data will be transferred **from** overseas only where contact information has been provided to University staff or agents in the course of making an enquiry about study at the University.

Data will only be transferred overseas to University staff based in the Dubai office to follow up on enquiries or applications from international students in that region. Information provided to the Dubai office will be subject to the same protection, processes and rights as data held in the UK.

Data stored in our database is transferred and saved on servers based in Canada. Transfers may be made where a third country, a territory or one or more specific sectors in the third country, or an international organisation ensures an adequate level of protection.

Canada has “adequacy” status from the European Commission, which determined in 2001 that Canada’s law under PIPEDA (the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act) was strong enough to satisfy that any data transferred from the EU to Canada would be adequately protected.

**How long do we keep this information for?**

Personal data will be held up to a maximum of 4 years. This is because we understand that your original enquiry to study may be for a later academic year and you may then have further educational needs as you progress through your original course of choice. If, at any time, you would like to stop receiving these communications you can contact as at [MarketingComms@bradford.ac.uk](mailto:MarketingComms@bradford.ac.uk) or update your contact preferences in the Your Bradford portal.

**What are your rights as a data subject?**

As a person whose personal data we are processing, you have certain rights in respect of that personal data; you have the right:

  * To withdraw consent;
  * To access your personal data that we process;
  * To rectify inaccuracies in personal data that we hold about you if it is inaccurate or incomplete;
  * To request the deletion or removal of your personal data where there is no compelling reason for its continued processing;
  * To restrict the processing of your personal data in certain ways;
  * To obtain your personal data for reuse;
  * To object certain processing of your personal data;
  * To complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office about the way in which we process your personal data.

For more information on any of this information, please contact the University’s Data Protection Officer, Matthew Stephenson, [data-protection@bradford.ac.uk](mailto:data-protection@bradford.ac.uk), University of Bradford, Richmond Road Bradford BD7 1DP
